A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1902-1914
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1902-1914
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.472 II
This collection consists of ca.4,800 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.)
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence and related papers (ca. 4,800 items) of President Edwin Anderson Alderman originally kept in the President's office and maintained in a separate file labelled "Personal."
Contents List
- General Records 1902-1914
  - Aa-Am Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 1)
  - An-Az Miscellaneous 1907-1912 (Box 1)
  - Ba Miscellaneous 1905-1912 (Box 1)
  - Be-Bi Miscellaneous 1905-1911 (Box 1)
  - Bl-Bu Miscellaneous, reference to YMCA Business Men's Convention; Union Theological Seminary, N.Y. offers Honorary Degree 1904-1914 (Box 1)
  - Ca-Cl Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 1)
  - Co-Cz, reference to the Official Jamestown Expo Blue Book (speech), the Boyson award, and Lady Nuglut's Journal 1905-1914 (Box 2)
  - Civic Forum Address 1907-1909 (Box 2)
  - Classics, Old and New 1906-1911 (Box 2)
  - Curry, J.L.M.--Memoirs (written by Alderman and Gordon) 1902-1913 (Box 2)
  - Curry, J.L.M.--Newspaper Clippings (re: biography) 1911 (Box 2)
  - Curry, J.L.M.--Statue 1903-1908 (Box 2)
  - DMiscellaneous Evans, Carnegie speaking at Hampton 1904-1912 (Box 3)
  - Daughters of the Confederacy--the Lee Prize 1907-1909, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Daughters of the Confederacy--The Lee Prize 1908-1909, newspaper clippings (Box 3)
  - EMiscellaneous 1905-1912 (Box 3)
  - FMiscellaneous, reference to the McIver Memorial Volume 1904-1914 (Box 3)
  - Financial Matters 1911-1914 (Box 4)
  - GMiscellaneous, reference to panic in furniture business; Civil Service Reform League; Minor Memorial Building;Timberlake and to politics 1905-1912 (Box 4)
  - Ha-He Miscellaneous 1907-1912 (Box 4)
  - Hi-Hy Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 4)
  - IMiscellaneous 1907-1910 (Box 4)
  - Invitations to Speak (1 of 9) 1905 (Box 4)
  - Invitations to Speak (2-9 of 9) 1907-1914 (Box 5)
  - JMiscellaneous 1905-1911 (Box 6)
  - KMiscellaneous 1905-1911 (Box 6)
  - LMiscellaneous, reference to United Daughter's Confederation 1905-1912 (Box 6)
  - Lake Mohonk Conference on International Arbitration 1907-1910 (Box 6)
  - Letter Book Pages 1905-1907 (Box 6)
  - MMiscellaneous 1905-1914, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Na-Ne, reference to Bulletin 3, letters, to wards to Lee and introduction of Honor System 1906-1914 (Box 7)
  - Ni-Ny 1905-1914 (Box 7)
  - Normal College, NYC--Presidency 1906-1908 (Box 7)
  - OMiscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 7)
  - Pa-Pe Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 7)
  - Petersburg Address 1909-1910 (Box 7)
  - Phi-Py Miscellaneous 1905-1912 (Box 7)
  - RMiscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 7)
  - Receipts 1907-1909 (Box 7)
  - Sa-Si Miscellaneous, reference to Arabic Stone--gift 1905-1914 (Box 7)
  - Sk-So Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 7)
  - Sp-Su Miscellaneous 1905-1913 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board-- A-D Miscellaneous 1904-1906 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Alabama 1907 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Arkansas 1907 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Atlanta Conference 1909 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board-- BMiscellaneous 1907 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Berry School 1907 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Budget 1907 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Wallace Butrick 1907-1909 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board-- CMiscellaneous 1907-1908 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Campaign Committee 1906-1907 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Children's Theatre 1906-1907 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--P. P. Claxton 1908 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Conference on Secondary Education 1906 (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board--Cooperative Education Association of Virginia 1907-1912, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Southern Education Board-- D-F Miscellaneous 1907 (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board-- E-L Miscellaneous 1904-1906 (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board--Executive Committee 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board--Farmer's Cooperative Demonstration Work 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board-- GMiscellaneous 1907 (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board--General Education Board 1907-1913, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board--General Education Board Reports (by J. Starr Murphy) 1906 (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board--Georgia 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board-- H-I Miscellaneous 1906-1908 (Box 9)
  - Southern Education Board--High School Representatives' Reports 1908 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board-- K-L Miscellaneous 1907 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board--Louisiana Bond Campaign and Finances (by J. B. Aswell) 1905 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board--Louisiana, Mississippi 1907 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board-- MMiscellaneous 1907-1908 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board-- M-O Miscellaneous 1904-1906 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board--Memphis Conference 1907-1908 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board--North Carolina 1904-1907 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board-- O-Q Miscellaneous n.d. (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board--Robert C. Ogden 1907-1909 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board-- P-Z Miscellaneous 1904-1906 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board--George F. Peabody 1907 (Box 10)
  - Southern Education Board--Pinehurst Conference 1907 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board-- RMiscellaneous 1907-1909 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board-- S-Z Miscellaneous 1907-1908 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board--Secondary Education in Virginia, reports 1907-1910 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board--South Carolina 1907-1908 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board--State Supervisors of Rural Schools 1912-1914 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board--Superintendents of State Schools 1907-1909 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board--Tennessee 1906-1909 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board--Virginia Secondary Education Reports (by Bruce Payne) 1905-1906 (Box 11)
  - Southern Education Board--Virginia Field Agent Reports and Financial Statements (by Robert Frazier) 1904-1906 (Box 11)
  - TMiscellaneous 1905-1912 (Box 12)
  - UMiscellaneous 1907-1912 (Box 12)
  - VMiscellaneous, reference to Chapel Hill 1905-1914 (Box 11)
  - Wa-Wh Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 11)
  - Washington University, Presidency 1907-1908 (Box 12)
  - Wi Miscellaneous 1905-1912 (Box 12)
  - Wo-Wy Miscellaneous 1905-1911 (Box 12)
  - X-Z Miscellaneous 1907-1909 (Box 12)